Subtitles brought to you by the Starry Love team 🌟 @ Viki
[Love like the galaxy 2]
[Episode 26]
Sister Shaoshang, that day my words were harsh.
I bragged about General Huo's affection for me.
I ask my sister to forgive me.
After my husband died, the people of the Luo family continued to force me.
They hoped I would get married and move up socially soon.
Otherwise, they will marry me again in the Northwest.
A woman like me who has nothing but my name, can be up to the task for my first marriage,
but there aren't many choices left for my second wedding.
So I was impatient.
So you clung to General Huo and wouldn't let him go.
I have had feelings for General Huo since I was young.
I hoped I could be with him.
It's a shame he doesn't think so.
The worst thing I've done
was to overestimate myself
and underestimating General Huo's affection for you.
I deserved public humiliation this time too.
General Huo, in front of so many people,
sent a mirror to my father and specified that it was for my dowry.
I dare not imagine
how humiliated my father was at that moment.
Don't look at me.
I don't want anything to do with him.
I will plead even less on your behalf with him.
I won't persuade him to marry you either. That's your own business.
Non.
A passing passion poorly invested for five years,
That's already enough.
How many five years can a woman have in her life?
Today I came to tell Sister Shaoshang
that I decided to return to the Northwest to live the rest of my days.
We will say goodbye in this life.
I've already found a carriage.
I will leave tonight.
My sister and General Huo must grow old together.
Otherwise, I will not accept it even if I am in the Northwest.
I've already given up my obsession with Huo Buyi now.
But I still have something to do
for Empress Xuan.
After Empress Xuan fell seriously ill,
General Huo still missed him in his heart.
Now General Huo has finally returned.
What about the Empress's illness now?
Imperial Physician Sun says his depression is deep.
Heart disease is difficult to treat. (Note: A mental illness)
This morning his illness worsened again.
She can't even get up anymore.
I understand.
Empress.
Is this Zisheng?
It's me.
You have lost weight.
I am worried about the capital.
I don't dare to relax.
Are you worried about the capital or...
Worried about Shaoshang?
There is something I want to tell you.
Yuan Shanjian and Shaoshang
are not engaged.
I know.
You are still in Shaoshang's heart.
I know that too.
I was wrong.
I have already decided...
to spend my whole life atoning for my sins.
When she needed love most in her youth,
she didn't receive any from her family.
If you want to love him,
so you must make amends for the regrets his heart has.
Don't always ask him to understand your choices.
You can both take the trip together
only if you talk about things.
Yes.
In the future, Shaoshang and I...
we will say everything and speak without reserve.
There will be no secrets.
It's a pity that time is too short.
I'm afraid I can't see you get married.
I, your child, am incompetent. (Note: He calls himself her child because he grew up in her palace)
I made you worry.
I just hope that in the next life,
you two can be my biological son and daughter.
I also hope that I can live a few more years
to smile all year round...
to have you both to take care of me until my old age.
This kind of life...
can be considered fulfilled.
Miss Luo, why haven't we reached the residence of the miracle doctor you mentioned?
Previously, I looked for medicine for the Seventh Young Master.
So I asked my family and friends to find the residencies of a bunch of highly qualified doctors in the capital.
In the end, I chose this person.
This doctor is really good at treating people with depression.
If Miss Cheng doesn't believe me, please return to Changqiu Palace.
I'm afraid Empress Xuan won't be able to bear it any longer.
Then stop the carriage first. I'll disturb Miss Luo.
so that she can tell me the exact location. After I return and report it to Her Majesty
I will bring sumptuous gifts during my visit.
Sister Shaoshang, you don't trust me?
Look. This carriage contains all my things.
I came to the capital with them. Now I'm leaving with nothing else.
I decided to go back to the Northwest.
Before I go, why should I hurt you?
Non-commissioned Officer Liang Qiufei passed on a message.
He asks General Huo to leave the palace to attend to an urgent matter.
Vas-y.
When you see Shaoshang, speak to him kindly.
She will understand you.
I will do it.
General Huo, Non-Commissioned Officer Liang Qiufei said that
Miss Cheng had left in Miss Luo's carriage
and that they had left the capital for the outskirts of the city.
When was it?
About an hour ago.
When you return to the Northwest, you will be able to choose a future spouse in peace.
If someone is right for you, you won't have to reluctantly settle down for the rest of your life.
Who said that if a young woman didn't have a husband, she couldn't live?
Younger sister really has no idea.
Apart from General Huo, I will never marry anyone else.
He is not the only man in the world.
Why should you cling to a single tree until you die?
You don't understand.
Since I was young, I have been attracted to General Huo.
But because of my modest status, I naturally did not dare to confess my feelings.
Later, we were each engaged on our own.
I thought there was no hope for this life.
Who would have known that Heaven decided to have mercy on me
and allowed me to find General Huo in the Northwest?
Younger Sister Shaoshang couldn't imagine how delighted I was at that moment.
It was like throwing a lifeline to someone about to drown.
So when you and your late husband were still married,
Were you already thinking about General Huo?
Do you know what it feels like to love someone deeply?
but that we must serve someone else with body and mind?
In bed, there wasn't a single moment when I wasn't thinking about him.
I even had to imagine Zisheng in Seventh Master Jia's place in order to bear it.
I didn't know.
You don't need to tell me such ridiculous things.
That's because you're clearly heartless.
Do you know what kind of life he led in the Northwest?
He charged the enemy lines and fought with his life.
Every time he fought a battle, others sought survival while he sought death.
You have such a cruel heart.
Why are you so ruthless with him?
Luckily, Zisheng has me.
I love him and respect him.
No matter what he does to me, I don't blame him.
I can accept its good and bad sides.
I'm different from a young lady like you who gets engaged and calls it off on a whim.
I lived a chaste life. And I only loved one person.
Miss Luo, if it weren't for Empress Xuan,
I would never have come here with you.
Stop the carriage.
Cheng Shaoshang! Because of you, Huo Buyi cut all ties with me.
Now that I have nowhere to go,
all the young ladies of the capital are waiting to make fun of me.
How could I let you get out of the carriage?
Let go of me. Let go of me!
Did you know that
The military doctors said that the bite scar on Zisheng's arm would never heal?
He even used medication to make his scar deeper. All because of you!
I was so bitterly deceived by you both.
You fooled yourself!
Let go of me!
He remains indifferent to all the other young ladies.
Why are you so special?
I entered the palace before you.
I am more intelligent and virtuous than you.
How come Huo Buyi only has eyes for you?
You really deserve to die.
Luo Jitong, even if you kill me, you won't get it.
So what?
For him, I'm ready to do anything!
I didn't even hesitate to kill my husband.
But he still doesn't love me.
As long as I kill you,
He will remember me forever. Even if he hates me with all his heart.
Stop the carriage!
Shaoshang!
Zisheng!
If you dare stop the carriage, I'll kill it on the spot!
Luo Jitong, la chez-la !
We can talk about everything else properly!
Talk ?
I begged you yesterday, yet your expression hasn't changed one iota.
But now you're afraid?
Well, if you want me to let her go, I can do that.
But you have to marry me. Can you accept that?
Let her go first. I'll accept anything!
Stop lying to me! You think I don't know?
that apart from Cheng Shaoshang, you have no intention of marrying anyone else? Since that's the case,
What's the point of continuing to live?
I'm going to die with her!
Shaoshang, tiens bon!
Hurry up and let go of me! With your skills, you should be able to climb.
If you don't let go of me now, we'll both die here.
Let go of me!
I won't let go unless I'm dead.
Huo Buyi.
Even if you die for me, I will not forgive you.
- Hurry up and let go of me! - I won't live without you!
I know. I've done too many bad things.
and I don't deserve your forgiveness.
But since we bit each other's arm like a bond,
I have already taken you as my wife.
So if you live, I live.
If you die,
I'm dying!
Young Lord, we are here!
Hold fast !
Shaoshang, hold on to the rope!
Your injury...
How are you.
Everything will be fine once the doctors have bandaged her.
Mademoiselle Cheng,
Let me walk you back to the palace.
It is not necessary.
I can leave on my own.
So let A'Qi take you back.
Take my carriage.
Is...
I'll leave first.
Report! General Huo. Miss Cheng.
His Majesty requests that you return to the palace immediately.
Empress Xuan...
Empress Xuan doesn't have much longer to live!
Shen'an, is there anything that
weighs on your heart?
Tell me, and I'll...
would definitely make it happen for you.
In my life,
I have always lived for others.
If I still spoke for others now
it would be too meaningless.
I have been at Your Majesty's side for several decades.
I know that Your Majesty's interests
are agriculture and academic research.
An upright and sincere young man.
If it were not for the disorder in the country
and the tyranny of Emperor Li,
Your Majesty would have liked to live peacefully in the countryside,
marry Sister Yue Heng,
have a few children,
get up at dawn to work until evening
and live a simple and peaceful life.
Shen'an,
of your whole life,
I am the one who...
who stood in your way.
Your Majesty, you owe me nothing.
I did not dare to challenge the marriage alliance made by my uncle.
Meet you...
was the chance of a lifetime.
Your Majesty...
has sacrificed too much for world peace.
It's the same for Sister A'Heng.
Under the pretext that she is courageous, direct
and that she speaks openly,
Your Majesty should not
not to think that she did not take this to heart
or that she didn't get her heart broken.
I know she probably cried more in secret.
than I did.
In the future,
Your Majesty and Sister A'Heng
must be good to each other,
just as you were close in the countryside,
as if I had never been there.
Older sister.
Your Majesty.
Yes ?
Let me talk to A'Heng.
All right.
Older sister.
As long as I, Yue Heng, am alive,
I will make sure the Xuan family is safe and sound.
Who is counting on you?
There is the crown prince.
He is calm and competent.
I have no worries.
Now I want to tell you about us.
That year, when my son faced an assassination attempt at nineteen,
I never doubted you.
I know.
That year,
My son died prematurely at four months old,
I never doubted you either.
I know that...
You never doubted me.
That's why you weren't afraid of gossip.
and accepted these children.
Older sister.
In my opinion,
we are like real sisters.
If we were
sisters in an ordinary family,
Wouldn't that be nice?
Let the children come now.
You can all come.
Slowly, slowly.
My body...
will be buried in the Imperial Mausoleum.
Will you allow me...
to cut a small lock of hair
for Shaoshang to make ashes of it
to wear in the mountains
where I lived during my childhood with my father?
Whatever you say, we will do it.
Son,
don't always be so indecisive.
No matter the fame.
People must live with an open mind
to be able to live a long time.
I will let you take care of Lady-in-waiting Zhai in her old age.
I would definitely take good care of Lady Companion Zhai.
Imperial Mother, please hold on. I still want to serve you later in your old age.
There is no later for me.
Imperial Mother, I was wrong.
I was wrong.
I want to exchange my life for yours.
If you are truly filial,
don't use your life to trade it for mine.
Live well.
Cherish your own good times. Don't lose yourself.
Zisheng.
Empress.
I disappointed you.
I never held it against you.
I know this has been hard for you
all along this path.
You don't owe us anything.
I know you had regrets.
When I'm gone,
let the past scatter with the wind.
You have to forgive yourself.
Shaoshang,
one.
I pulled you down
for five years now.
What do you mean, pulled down?
I am always ready to follow the Empress...
five more years, ten more years...
Idiot.
How many five years or ten years are there in a person's life?
You've already lost a lot for my sake.
I hope that in the coming days,
you will live a good life for yourself.
I don't want you to...
waste the rest of your life like I did.
As a mother, I hope you two
will be able to take back your destined love.
But as a sensitive elder,
I also know that a marriage cannot be forced.
I just want to rush you both
to always follow your heart,
to appreciate the present, and not regret it.
In my next life,
I hope I will live in a prosperous and peaceful era
and that I will suffer less from homesickness and unrest.
In my next life,
I hope my parents live long and healthy lives...
for fear that I have worry or sorrow.
In my next life,
I hope to be able to compose poetry in my youth
and sing in the mountainous deserts.
My husband,
Marrying you was a stroke of luck in my life.
But in the next life, I hope you and I...
we won't... see each other... again.
General Huo, let's go talk somewhere else.
GOOD.
What exactly happened?
Empress Xuan has passed away.
You can both rest assured.
I only came to take Shaoshang home.
I will leave immediately and not disturb you.
Huo Buyi, stop right there!
General Huo, what do you think the Marquis of Quling's Residence is?
Who do you think our Niao Niao is?
Can you come whenever you want and leave whenever you want?
Just like years ago when you were about to marry her, but you abandoned her.
Five years ago, you abandoned Niao Niao.
She was so sick that she almost died.
Go to the warehouse in the backyard to take a look.
The half-built coffin for her is still there!
I know I have deeply disappointed Shaoshang.
I also know how much you love and care for Shaoshang.
That's why...
I have decided never to bother you again.
Do you know how Niao Niao has lived these past five years?
She loved the excitement and excitement more than anything.
But she cloistered herself in Changqiu Palace for those entire five years.
I was in pain and couldn't get better.
His older brother got married. His older cousin started a family.
We were all looking forward to seeing her again for that.
But she never set foot outside Changqiu Palace.
You lost her for five years.
Our Cheng family also lost our daughter for five years!
Do you know who she did this for?
For you,
Huo Buyi.
It's all my fault.
I abandoned Shaoshang despite all the love she had for me.
I abandoned the Cheng family despite your trust in me.
I'm sorry to Shaoshang.
I also apologize to the Cheng family.
What I owe you cannot be paid in my entire life.
Not to mention the fact that Shaoshang can't forgive me,
even me...
I will never be able to forgive myself.
In the Northwest,
I fought and killed without caring whether it was day or night.
I only wished that the blade of a sword would pierce my chest and leave me to die on the battlefield.
But I didn't dare to die either.
I haven't yet managed to make him forget his hateful resentment.
I have no right to die.
General Huo,
We are not asking you to admit your guilt.
What we just said was not to make you feel guilty.
As Niao Niao's parents,
We haven't given her enough love and care since she was young.
It is also too late for us to regret it.
In the future, no matter which road Niao Niao takes, and who she marries,
We will let her decide from now on.
Between you, one has love, the other has heart.
What a pity that Heaven is playing tricks on us.
As for whether you can get your previous condition back,
take it step by step and wait and see.
[Special Announcement: The cliff fall scene was created using CGI special effects and horse props.]
Subtitles brought to you by the Starry Love team 🌟 @ Viki
♫ The flames of war strike against the frost and snow ♫
♫ It gently covers up that lingering illness from the past ♫
♫ You turn your back on the light, the galaxy is reflected in your eyes ♫
♫ I hum a tune, the sun and the moon answer me ♫
♫ The sparkle that enters these eyes ♫
♫ Was extinguished by dust and lights up again ♫
♫ The borders of Earth, Kunlun, and the Beyond feel remorse for one person ♫
♫ The ocean awakens, the forest of stelae is like a mountain range ♫
♫ There are veiled criticisms in this corridor, a small door cannot easily close the intentions of some ♫
♫ One person's challenges become advice for the future ♫
♫ You and I, we will be in the same galaxy ♫
♫ We will use our full sincerity to bring brilliance to the ordinary ♫
♫ Bringing brightness to the ordinary ♫